drugabuse.com 2017-09-22

# Privacy Policy | DrugAbuse.com

## Website Privacy Policy

**Effective Date: 10/01/2015**

This Privacy Policy covers the information appearing on the website on which it is posted (“Website” or “Site”), which is operated by Recovery Brands LLC, part of Sober Media Group (“Recovery Brands”, “DrugAbuse.com”, “Sober Media Group” or “we”).  This Privacy Policy is designed to tell you about our practices regarding collection, use, and disclosure of information that you may provide via this Website and certain related services. Please be sure to read this entire Privacy Policy before using, or submitting information, to this Website.  By accessing the Site on any computer, mobile phone, tablet, or other device (collectively, “Device”), you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the policy, please do not use the Website.

We may modify this Privacy Policy at any time. If we decide to change this Privacy Policy, we will post those changes on our Website. We encourage you to periodically review our Privacy Policy to stay informed about how we are using the information we collect.

## Collection of Information

### Personal Information

We collect personal information from you when you provide it to us, including by providing information to us to find a treatment facility, or when you contact us.  This information may include, for example, your email address, name, telephone phone number, or mailing address.

### Non-Personal Information

When you visit the Website, we may collect certain non-personal information from you, including your Internet Protocol (IP) address, the date and time of your visit, browser type, operating system, the specific web pages visited during your connection, and the domain name from which you accessed the Website. In addition, we may collect information about your browsing behavior, such as the date and time you visit the Website, the areas or pages of the Website that you visit, the amount of time you spend viewing the Website, the number of times you return to the Website and other clickstream data. We may also use non-personal information for statistical analysis, research, and other purposes.

Like many commercial websites, we may analyze how visitors use our Site through what is known as “cookie” technology.  A cookie is a small text file that is placed on your computer when you access the Site and allows us to recognize you each time you visit the Site. We may use cookies to: (1) enhance or personalize your Website usage; (2) monitor Site usage; (3) manage the Website; and (4) improve the Website and our services. If you choose, you can set your browser to reject cookies or you can manually delete individual or all of the cookies on your computer by following your browser’s help file directions. However, if your browser is set to reject cookies or you manually delete cookies, you may have some trouble accessing and using some of the pages and features that are currently on our Website, or that we may put on our Website in the future.

We may also use web beacons on the Website, in our emails and in our advertisements on other websites. Web beacons are tiny graphic images that are used to collect information about your Site visit, such as the pages you view and the features you use, as well as information about whether you open and/or act upon one of our emails or advertisements. We may also collect the URL of the website you visited immediately before coming to the Website. Web beacons help us analyze our Website visitors’ behavior and measure the effectiveness of the Website and our advertising. We may work with service providers that help us track, collect and analyze this and other site usage information.

We may combine the non-personal information we collect, such as through cookies and web beacons, with other information we have collected from you.

### Use of Information

We may use the information we collect from and about you for any of the following purposes: (1) to improve the quality of the content available on our sites, administer the sites, and enable certain functionality such as your participation in interactive areas of the sites (2) to provide you with names of treatment centers; (3) to respond to your inquiries; (4) to review Website usage and operations; (5) to address problems with the Website, our business or our services; (6) to protect the security or integrity of the Site and our business; (7) to monitor the Site for compliance with our Terms of Use and the law; and (8) to contact you with Website updates, newsletters and other informational and promotional materials from us and third party marketing offers from our trusted partners, as well as from other companies.

If you do not wish to receive communications from us about special offers and promotions, you can opt-out of receiving these communications by emailing us at removal@recoverybrands.com, or by following the instructions contained in the messages you receive.

## Disclosure of Information

We may disclose information collected from and about you as follows: (1) to select companies and organizations so that they may use it for their own marketing and promotional uses; (2) to our related companies and service providers, to perform a business, professional or technical support function for us; (3) as necessary if we believe that there has been a violation of the Website Terms of Use or of our rights or the rights of any third party; (4) to respond to legal process (such as a search warrant, subpoena or court order) and provide information to law enforcement agencies or in connection with an investigation on matters related to public safety, as permitted by law, or otherwise as required by law; and (5) in the event that our company or substantially all of its assets are acquired, your personal information may be one of the transferred assets. We may also disclose your personal information with your express consent for other purposes not listed here. We may share aggregate, non-personally identifiable information about Website users with third parties.

While DrugAbuse.com seeks to share personally-identifying information with companies that follow appropriate privacy policies, it does not bear any responsibility for the actions and policies of such third parties. If you prefer that we not share your information with third parties, you may “opt out” by contacting us with that request. You should be aware that any information you post on a bulletin board, forum, comment space, or “chat” room or that you otherwise specifically and knowingly disclose during the use of the Site, may be directly collected and used by third parties. As a result of disclosing such information, you may be subject to unsolicited email. You should have no expectation of privacy with respect to your communications through the forums or your profile should you choose to list this information.

## Security

We maintain reasonable and appropriate measures designed to maintain information we collect in a secure manner.  We have taken certain physical, electronic, and administrative steps to safeguard and secure the information we collect from Website visitors.  Even though we follow reasonable procedures to try to protect the information in our possession, no security system is perfect and we cannot promise, and you should not expect, that your information will be secure in all circumstances.

## Email Policies

DrugAbuse.com will use reasonable means to protect the privacy of the information you send us by email. However, because of the risks outlined below, DrugAbuse.com cannot guarantee that email communications will be confidential. Additionally, DrugAbuse.com will not be liable in the event that you or anyone else inappropriately uses your email.

## Interest Based Advertising

We may partner with ad networks and other ad serving providers (“Advertising Providers”) who serve ads on behalf of us and others on non-affiliated sites. Some of those ads may be personalized, meaning that they are intended to be relevant to you based on information Advertising Providers collect about your visits to this site and elsewhere over time.

You may visit www.aboutads.info to learn more about this type of advertising and how to opt-out of this form of advertising by companies participating in the Digital Advertising Alliance (“DAA”) self-regulatory program.  Note that electing to opt-out will not stop advertising from appearing in your browser or applications.  It may make the ads you see less relevant to your interests.  In addition, note that if you use a different browser or erase cookies from your browser, you may need to renew your opt-out choice. 

## Children

We do not direct the Website to, nor do we knowingly collect any personal information from, children under the age of thirteen.

## Your California Privacy Rights

California law permits our customers who are California residents to request certain information about our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes.  To make such a request, please contact us by emailing [privacy@recoverybrands.com](mailto:privacy@recoverybrands.com).

## Third Party Websites

The Site may contain links to third-party websites which may have privacy policies that differ from our own. We are not responsible for, nor do we endorse, any of the activities and practices that take place on these sites. Accordingly, we recommend that you review the privacy policy posted on any external site before disclosing any personal information.  Please contact those websites directly if you have any questions about their privacy policies. 

## Contact Us

If you have questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy, you can contact us by emailing [contact@recoverybrands.com](mailto:contact@recoverybrands.com).  If we need, or are required, to contact you concerning any event that involves your information, we may do so by email, telephone, or mail.

##  About the DrugAbuse.com Toll-Free Helpline and Directory 

Each year, the DrugAbuse.com hotline connects thousands of people with substance abuse treatment programs throughout the U.S. toll-free. Calls are answered by American Addiction Centers (AAC) who have treatment support specialists available 24/7, 365 days a year. 

Both our treatment directory and our hotline are offered at no cost to you. 

##  Where Else Can I Find Help? 

**National Hotlines:**

SAMHSA Facility Locator - <http://findtreatment.samhsa.gov/index.html> 1-800-662-HELP (4357) Free and confidential information in English and Spanish for individuals and family members facing substance abuse and mental health issues. 24 hours a day, 7 days a week. 

Suicide Prevention Lifeline - <http://www.suicidepreventionlifeline.org/> 1-800-273-TALK (8255) 24-hour, toll-free, confidential suicide prevention hotline available to anyone in suicidal crisis or emotional distress. Your call is routed to the nearest crisis center in the national network of more than 150 crisis centers. 

American Association of Poison Control Centers - <http://www.aapcc.org/> For a poisoning emergency in the U.S. call 1-800-222-1222 The American Association of Poison Control Centers supports the nation’s 55 poison centers in their efforts to prevent and treat poison exposures. Poison centers offer free, confidential medical advice 24 hours a day, seven days a week 

**Nonprofit Treatment Centers:**

Betty Ford Center - <http://www.bettyfordcenter.org/index.php>

Phoenix House - <http://www.phoenixhouse.org/>

Caron - <http://www.caron.org/>

Odyssey House - <http://www.odysseyhouse.org/>

Recovery Gateway - <http://recovergateway.org/>

Dawn Farm - <http://dawnfarm.org/>

Austin Recovery - <http://www.austinrecovery.org/>

**Recovery Programs:**

Alcoholics Anonymous - <http://www.aa.org/>

Narcotics Anonymous - <http://www.na.org/>

Smart Recovery - <http://www.smartrecovery.org/>
